Paul Aderoju

Fullstack Software Engineer

8B, Pilot Close, Yaba, Lagos, Nigeria. (+234)-808-904-5470 paul.adeboye@yahoo.com

PROJECTS

<u>Healing Spring Hospital</u> — Fertility Clinic

<u>Portfolio</u> — My portfolio website.

Empathy Space — Mental Health Startup.

<u>Builder.io Event Launch App</u> —AI Company Event Launch App.

<u>**Artmo**</u> — Management Consulting Firm.

<u>NextJS Login Page</u> —Login Page built with NextJS and Tailwind.

Phonie — Nigerian Mobile carrier detector.

EDUCATION

University of Helsinki, Remote

2023 - 2024

Full Stack Software Development.

ALX, Remote — Nanodegree

2023 - 2024

Cloud Engineering.

AltSchool Africa, Remote — Diploma

2022 - 2023

Software Engineering.

University of Lagos, Nigeria—Bachelor's Degree

2015 - 2021

Dentistry and Dental Surgery.

St. Finbarr's College, Akoka. Nigeria— Secondary School

2008 - 2014

Senior Secondary School Certificate Examination.

PROFILE SUMMARY

Paul Aderoju is a Fullstack Software Engineer and Health-tech enthusiast who has worked with JavaScript, React JS, NextJS, Python, Django, MySQL, and Databases for 18 months. He is exceptional at converting designs and wireframes into high-quality code, and implementing business logic and database systems. He has served in several leadership capacities in various student-led organizations, locally and internationally. He has a keen interest in implementing technology and finance to solve challenges in healthcare systems in Africa.

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS.

Fullstack Software Development Certification: <u>Fullstack Software</u> <u>Development Certification</u>

AWS Cloud Computing -ALX:

- <u>AWS Cloud Computing Certification</u>
- AWS Solutions Architect Associate
- AWS Cloud Practitioner

Full Stack Software Development: through the Zuri & I4G scholarship.

Paul Aderoju - Zuri Fullstack Certific...

Cloud Engineering Diploma Certification:
Paul Aderoju - Cloud Engineering
Diploma Certificate

Data Analysis using Excel-Rice University: *Link to Certificate*

Basic Data Descriptors, Statistical
Distribution, and Application to Business
Decisions-Rice University: <u>Link to</u>

WORK EXPERIENCE

Google Developer Students' Club — College of Medicine, *University of Lagos*

2022 - 2024

As a Google Developer Student Club (GDSC) Lead, I organized and led a community of student developers, planning and executing workshops, hackathons, and tech talks. I provided mentorship and training to members while partnering with industry professionals and university departments. Additionally, I oversaw club projects to ensure the practical application of technical skills and promoted GDSC activities to increase campus visibility and participation.

AWS Cloud Club Captain — *University of Lagos*

2023 - 2024

I was selected by AWS Academic Advocate Team to create the pioneer student-led cloud-focused group, which is focused on equipping students with skills in cloud computing, including Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Serverless, Storage, etc. I have grown the club to over 100 individuals in the space of 2 months.

Software Engineer — *Zijemu*

2022 - PRESENT

I work with a team of designers, mobile and web developers to deliver IoT solutions to clients in Nigeria.

Student Leader in Global Oral Health— Alliance for Oral Health Across Borders.

2022 - 2023

I was one of the few selected Africans and one of the 34 successful candidates selected as a student leader in the Student Leadership in Global Oral Health cohort from different countries globally. I worked with a colleague on a <u>project</u> to create awareness on Periodontitis in a community in Lagos State, Nigeria. I partnered with key stakeholders such as the Ministry of Health, and Lagos State Primary Healthcare Board to have a health intervention done.

Co-Founder — COPE Health

2022 - PRESENT

2022 Fuel Africa Healthcare Innovation Hackathon, where I led a team of five individuals that pitched an idea for improving the management of patients with non-communicable diseases such as hypertension and diabetes by leveraging a mobile application to increase compliance with their treatment process. I am currently working with my team to develop a minimum-viable product.

Software Engineer Intern — GSASConnect Global Ltd.

2022

I worked as a Fullstack software engineer, and designed the database schema, and led the team of developers that worked closely with designers.

Certificate

Inspiring and Motivating
Individuals – University of Michigan: <u>Link</u>
to Certificate

Health Financing for Universal Coverage-World Health Organization:

■ Aderoju Paul-WHO Health Financing f...

United Nations Academic Impact-Millennium Fellow:

■ Millennium fellowship certificate – Pau...

Health Financing for Universal Coverage — World Health Oragnization.

2021

I completed a course on Health Financing for Universal Health Coverage by the World Health Organization(W.H.O), where I learned the various Health Financing models that accelerate equitable access to quality health services, especially in underserved populations.

Millennium Fellow — United Nations Academic Impact

2019 - PRESENT

I was nominated as the Assistant General Secretary of the pioneer cohort in my campus and worked to ensure the success of our project themed M.A.A.D (Medical Students Against the Abuse of Drugs) focused on Sustainable Development Goals 3 – Good Health and Wellbeing, particularly Section 5, which seeks to Strengthen the prevention and treatment of substance abuse, by drafting letters to stakeholders and sponsors, and facilitating meetings with them.

Financial Secretary, General Secretary, Vice President — KB KLUB, College of Medicine, University of Lagos.

2018 - 2020

I have contributed to raising awareness about the Global Goals since becoming a member of the KB KLUB. I have organized three healthcare innovation events under the theme "STACK REFORM" as a lead member of the organization, serving as its Financial Secretary, General Secretary, and Vice President for 3 consecutive years. In 2019, I led the organization in executing an Opthalmology Medical Outreach by partnering with Eye Foundation Hospital and offering free eye screening tests to over 200 members of Epe Community in Lagos, and free cataract surgeries for the geriatric population in the same community. A local news agency described it as the first of its kind in the community.